<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers | Blogs on Ruan Pretorius</title>
    <link>https://ruankie.github.io/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Papers | Blogs on Ruan Pretorius</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 23:39:49 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ruankie.github.io/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On the naivety of ML models and how to avoid the naive trap</title>
      <link>https://ruankie.github.io/publications/naive-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruankie.github.io/publications/naive-ml/</guid>
      <description>See original article here&#xA;The naive trap When forecasting stock price movements with fancy ML models, you want your models to learn something useful from the provided data that humans might not be aware of so you have a competitive edge. This article will show you examples of where those fancy ML models learn something dumb that looks intelligent and how to check if your models are doing the same.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Reinforcement Learning and Convex Mean-Variance Optimisation for Portfolio Management</title>
      <link>https://ruankie.github.io/publications/rl-pm-msc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 16:21:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruankie.github.io/publications/rl-pm-msc/</guid>
      <description>See full paper here&#xA;Abstract Traditional portfolio management methods can incorporate specific investor preferences but rely on accurate forecasts of asset returns and covariances. Reinforcement learning (RL) methods do not rely on these explicit forecasts and are better suited for multi-stage decision processes. To address limitations of the evaluated research, experiments were conducted on three markets in different economies with different overall trends. By incorporating specific investor preferences into our RL models’ reward functions, a more comprehensive comparison could be made to traditional methods in risk-return space.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
